ROHIT SHARMA

Security analyst

 Polhi,India

 ☑ sharmarohit64187@gmail.com

 ↓ +917827066623

 ☑ Male

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/r0x5r/ ♥ https://github.com/r0x5r ★ https://r0x5r.github.io

PROFILE

I'm a Cybersecurity enthusiast with 1 years of experience in Web Application Penetration Testing . I enjoy learning new things, and the best way to learn is the practical way. So, I have a presence on various platforms like Tryhackme, HackTheBox, LetsDefend. I can detect and exploit most of the common vulnerabilities of a web application or a network. I also have knowledge of OWASP security principles.

P SKILLS

- Basic Programming and Scripting Languages: Python, Bash Scripting
- Tools: Metasploit, Nmap, Burp Suite, Nikto, Dirbuster, WebInspect, Acunetix, Kali Linux, Freshdesk
- Technologies: Linux, SAST, DAST, Networking, SOC, OSI, TCP/IP
- Frameworks and Methodology: OWASP Top 10, Sans 25, Mitre
- Technical Skills: Vulnerability Assessment, CTF Player, Web Application Security,
- Network Security, Incident Response, Report Writing, Bug Bounty, IT Security, Application testing, API Security Testing,
- Mobile (Android/iOS) application security testing, Secure code review, SOAP, REST, Black Box/WhiteBox testing

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Cyber Security Summer Internship, *SafeHouse* □

Jul 2021 – Aug 2021 | Gurugram, India

Skills: Cryptography \cdot Cybercrime Investigation \cdot Email Security \cdot Source Intelligence \cdot Cyberlaw \cdot Ethical Hacking

Junior Web Application Penetration Tester,

Jan 2023 – Present | Remote

ClustTech Innovations

- Conducted vulnerability assessments and penetration tests on web applications, addressing OWASP Top 10 and SANS 25, utilizing tools like Burp Suite, OWASP ZAP, and Nmap.
- Analyzed test results, providing actionable recommendations for enhancing application security.
- Collaborated with development teams, prioritizing and remediating identified vulnerabilities.
- Stayed current on the latest security threats, vulnerabilities, and industry best practices.
- Documented findings and methodologies in detailed reports for stakeholders.
- Actively participated in security training and knowledge-sharing activities.
- Contributed to the development and implementation of web application security policies and standards.

ACHIEVEMENTS

CVE 2022-3774 🖸 Nov 2022

A vulnerability was found in SourceCodester Train Scheduler App 1.0 and classified as critical

CVE-2023-5302 🖸 Sep 2023

A vulnerability has been found in SourceCodester Best Courier Management System 1.0 and classified as a meduim

Hall Of Fame, APPLE INC *8

Oct 2022

https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201536 [Rohit Sharma] July 2021

https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201536 [Rohit Sharma] August 2021

https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201536 [Rohit Sharma from Craw Security Pvt Ltd] June 2022

https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201536 [Rohit Sharma] August 2022

https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201536 [Rohit (r0x5r)] September 2022

https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201536 [Rohit Sharma] October 2022

https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201536 [ROHIT SHARMA (r0x5r)] February 2023

https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201536 [Rohit Sharma (r0x5r)] April 2023

Acknowledegement, *Lenovo Information Security* □

May 2022

https://drive.google.com/file/d/1-GZy0CFOcos0hkX4ujPYMoPFtft4UU2Z/view?usp=sharing ☑

Hall Of Fame, RedHat Inc □

Jul 2022

https://access.redhat.com/articles/66234

Appreciation Letter, *Drexel Edu* □

Sep 2022

https://drive.google.com/file/d/1pnmtMO6X2Hdz7CBkBCCYRrqp9GUbFzYe/view

Hall Of Fame ☐ https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/security/acknowledgements/ ☐

Oct 2022

Many More ☑

https://www.linkedin.com/in/r0x5r/details/honors/

EDUCATION

CBSE, class X 2018 | Delhi India

CBSE, Class XII 2020 | Delhi India

Craw Security, Cyber Security Diploma □

Sep 2020 – Aug 2021 | Delhi, India

- ETHICAL HACKING | MOBILE APPLICATION SECURITY
- CYBER FORENSICS & INVESTIGATION | PYTHON |
- PENETRATION TESTING | CRITICAL WEB APPLICATION VULNERABILITY | ADVANCED NETWORKING

Mewar Institute of Management,

Aug 2021 – present | India

Bachelors Computer Application